Vodou religious expression in Haiti collected by Odette Mennesson Rigaud, Milo Rigaud, and Shirley Keller
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
Vodou religious expression in Haiti collected by Odette Mennesson Rigaud, Milo Rigaud, and Shirley Keller 1944-1985
AFC 2019/041
Rigaud, Milo, 1904-1981, collector
Mennesson-Rigaud, Odette, collector
104 items
1 folder (21 sheets)
1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
11 sound tape reels: analog; 7 in.
1 sound tape reel: analog; 5 in.
50 sound wire reels: analog; 3 in.
17 audiocassettes: analog
1 videocassette (Hi-8): sound, color
1 DVD-R: sound, color
1 file: digital, sound, color; .vob
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
The collection includes audio documentation of religious expression in Haiti, circa 1940s-1950s.
Provenance
Scott Keller; Donation; 2019.
Custodial History
Shirley Keller received the wire recordings from Odette Mennesson Rigaud on an unspecified date.
Accruals
No accruals are expected.
Related Materials
Diane Wolkstein collection (AFC 2016/057)
Maya Deren Collection (#515), Howard Gotlieb Archival Research Center, Boston University.
Shirley Keller Collection (#20266-z), Southern Folklife Collection, The Wilson Library, University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill.
Fonds Odette Mennesson Rigaud/Milo Rigaud, Bibliothèque Haïtienne des Spiritains, Port-au-Prince, Haiti.
Access and Restrictions
The collection is open to research. To request materials, please contact the Folklife Reading Room at https://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/folklife.contact
Certain restrictions to use or copying of materials may apply.
Biographical Note
Odette Mennesson-Rigaud
Odette Mennesson-Rigaud (1907-1990) was born in France and became a Haitian citizen following her marriage to Milo Rigaud (in New York City, on January 10, 1935). She became an ethnographer of Vodou, and was a noted photographer in her own right.
Milo Rigaud
Milo Rigaud (1904-1981) was born in Port au Prince, Haiti, where he spent the greater part of his life studying Vodou traditions. In Haiti he also studied law, and in France ethnology, psychology, and theology. The involvement of Vodou in the political struggle of Haitian Blacks for independence was one of his main concerns.
Shirley Keller
Shirley Keller (-2017) of New Jersey was a white folk singer and musician who played guitar, Appalachian dulcimer, auto harp, and banjo. In the 1980s and 1990s, Keller hosted a weekly radio program on WFDU FM Radio and later a cable television show in New Jersey and New York called "The Folk People." She interviewed guest folk musicians and artists, who also performed in the studio.
Scope and Content
The collection includes audio documentation of religious expression in Haiti, circa 1940s-1950s, as well as an audio interview with Shirley Keller about her work on the book The Magic Orange Tree and a video of a presentation she gave with Angus Gillespie on vodou traditions. The wires appear to be the source recordings for the 1953 Rigaud book La tradition voudoo et le voudoo haïtien: (son temple, ses mystères, sa magie). Most of the sound tape recordings are compiled dubs of wire recordings.
Arrangement
The collection is organized in four series:
Series 1: Manuscripts
Series 2: Vodou-related recordings
Series 3: Various sound recordings
Series 4: Dubbed commercial recordings
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Gaither, Edmund B.--Interviews.; Gillespie, Angus K., 1942-; Keller, Shirley (Guitarist); Keller, Shirley (Guitarist)--Interviews.; Mennesson-Rigaud, Odette; Mennesson-Rigaud, Odette--Interviews.; Rigaud, Milo, 1904-1981; Robinson, Rudy, 1937-1987--Interviews.
Subjects
Drum music--Haiti.; Folklore--Haiti.; Percussion music--Haiti.; Vodou music--Haiti.; Vodou--Haiti.; Vodou--Rituals--Haiti.
Places
Haiti--Religion.; Haiti--Religious life and customs.
Titles
Milo and Odette Rigaud Haiti recordings
Form/Genre
Correspondence.; Interviews.; Sound recordings.; Video recordings.
Container List
- Series 1: Manuscripts
  - Documents related to the collection, 1940s, after 2001 (Box-folder 1/1)
    Includes documentation from sound recording containers, original and photocopied instructions on how to use a wire recorder, a handwritten note from Odette Rigaud to Shirley Keller, and a handwritten letter from Odette Rigaud to an unidentified person (implicitly identified as Shirley Keller, see afc2019041_dc001_aip_01 for details).
- Series 2: Vodou-related recordings
  Information transcribed from audio containers and carriers has been edited for clarity (e.g., some abbreviations have been expanded). Tape recordings seem to be primarily dubs of wire recordings, and as such the audio quality reflects the original recording, as well as any imperfections introduced in the dubbing process.
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 2019/041: SR001; WIRE 01063; 1 sound wire reel (Webster-Chicago, approx. 00:10:00): analog
    Transcriptions:
    Box panel: 1 / Passe / Concher Ciceron / Au Revoir / [?]onper debut [?] ajartes [?] 10' c[?] / de rondeau II a fin / milieu en fin excellents / Rerecording sur tape No 6-7
    Box lid: 1 Tape 6-7 / 60' / Concher Ciceron
    Written on the wire spool: passé / Concher Ciceron / rerecorded tape 6-7
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 2019/041: SR002; WIRE 01064; 1 sound wire reel (Webster-Chicago, approx. 00:08:00): analog
    Box panel 1: 21 / concher Ciceron / [?] - 8' / tape rerecording No 7
    Box panel 2: 21 / Odette Rigaud / 21
    Box lid: Concher Ciceron 8 / Tape 7 / 21
    Written on the wire spool: passé / Concher Ciceron 4 / 8' 2 / rerecording son tape [?]
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 2019/041: SR003; WIRE 01065; 1 sound wire reel (Webster-Chicago, approx. 00:55:00): analog
    Box panel: I - Ciceron son des differentés danses / Rada / 55'
    Box lid: Ciceron son Rada / 55' approx.
    Written on the wire spool: 55' / I / Ciceron son des diverses danses Rada
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 2019/041: SR004; WIRE 01066; 1 sound wire reel (Webster-Chicago, approx. 00:30:00): analog; One of the spool flanges is chipped; the piece accompanies the spool.
    Box panel: Ciceron 30' / son differentes danses / Congo - Petro / Pangole
    Box lid: Ciceron sons Congo - Petro 30'
    Written on the wire spool: II Ciceron sons differéntés danses / Congo - Petro / 30'
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 2019/041: SR005; WIRE 01067; 1 sound wire reel (approx. 00:20:00): analog
    Box panel: passé 10' ca Ciceron à revoir chantes divers 10' / 10' vierge
    Box lid: Ciceron chantes divers
    Written on the wire spool: efforce 20' / [?]
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 2019/041: SR006; WIRE 01068; 1 sound wire reel (Webster-Chicago, approx. 00:04:00): analog
    Box panel: Ciceron 4' / bohoun / bohoun / appel [?]ondé [?] morts / Songs of the Dead
    Box lid: Ciceron - bohouns
    Written on the wire spool: Cicéron - bohouns
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 2019/041: SR007; WIRE 01069; 1 sound wire reel (Silvertone, approx. 00:13:00): analog
    Box panel: effacé / 13' 15' / Ciceron - histoires / [?] jais bien / -[?] chien jappé / -[?] mu[?] pas fait par[?] / -[?] couleure r[?]
    Box lid: Ciceron - histoires 2
    Written on the wire spool (front): histoires Ciceron 13'
    Written on the wire spool (back): effacé 13'
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 2019/041: SR008; RXK 3578; 1 sound reel (acetate, 00:48:00): analog, 7 1/2 ips; half track, mono; 7 in.
    Summary:
    The content fades in about 00:00:19. A male singer (probably Cicéron), with multiple voices singing at times. Conversations can be heard in the background. The recording includes the following instruments: drums, a rattle, a whistle, and perhaps other instruments. Some hand clapping can be heard. The audio crackles intermittently, probably from the source recording. The recording fades in and out at times, and ends abruptly. The tape was probably was dubbed from one or more wire recordings.
    Box panel: Rerecording 1 Concher Ciceron 50' [?] sur [?] 7
    Information from the donor (written on the tape box): Tape 6 to cassette 6 / April 1982 by Shirley Keller / Odette was Voodoo [sic] Priestess from 1950's / Voodoo [sic] from wire recordings of Odette Rigaud of Port au Prince Haiti
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 2019/041: SR009; RXK 3579; 1 sound reel (acetate, 00:48:00): analog, 7 1/2 ips; half track, mono; 7 in.
    The content fades in about 00:00:07. Male singer (probably Cicéron), with multiple voices singing at times. The recording includes drums, metal percussion, a rattle, and perhaps other instruments. Some hand clapping can be heard. The recording fades in and out at times, and ends abruptly. The tape was probably was dubbed from one or more wire recordings.
    Box panel: Rerecording (1) Concher Ciceron (suite) 10' / Rerecording (2) Concher Ciceron 8' / Rerecording (3) Canzo Ciceron (début) / 7 - should be 5
    Information from the donor (written on the tape box): Re-recorded on to Cassette #7 May 1982 by Shirley Keller
    Written on the tape reel flange: Rerecorded on to Cassette #7 May 1982 by Shirley Keller
    Accompanying documentation: Rerecording (1) Concher Ciceron (suite) 10' / Rerecording (2) Concher Ciceron 8' / Re-recording (3) / Canzo Ciceron (début)
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 2019/041: SR010; RXK 3580; 1 sound reel (acetate, 00:48:00): analog, 7 1/2 ips; half track, mono; 7 in.
    The content starts at 00:00:05. Speech and a cappella singing, with some conversation and laughter, and possibly recitations. A baby can be heard crying occasionally. Some hand clapping can be heard. The recording includes drums can be heard; there may be other instruments played. The recording ends abruptly. The recording ends abruptly. Dubbed from one or more source recordings (probably wires).
    The note "Made on Ito's machine (Webster)" is probably a reference to Teiji Ito, composer and drummer, who met Maya Deren in 1955 and traveled with her to Haiti. He may have loaned the wire recorder to the Rigauds.
    Box panel [listed thus]:
    Rerecording (M) V - commencé sur 4
    Zaca Titon et Julia chants
    arrivée de Ogon - Julia Ogon
    Zaca Titon - venue Ogon [erased word] Titon
    chants Wago paroles Issange [?] [duege Malo?]
    Venue de entretoutt
    Histoires Entre toutt - Chants
    Titon Martinique "Sina"
    Titon Martinique "Jouda [?]porte" "Amude" [?]
    Titon Martinique A l'assant
    Titon Martinique Erzulie Dantor
    O loa rele Loas o Dantor javné[?]
    Avanncé[?] o Z'arezs[?] non d'leau
    Recordist's note:
    Made on Ito's machine (Webster) [wire recorder]
    Tape leader:
    Head - Debut. Rerecording No 5. Vodou. 2e rerecording (M) V
    Accompanying documentation:
    11 wire / 2 copies sur tape moins 1 (priere) no 8 manqour [?] - reste in Boston / Rerecording 3 [?] [?] de Canzo Ciceron / et 19 non mis sur tape
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 2019/041: SR011; RXK 3581; 1 sound reel (acetate, 00:25:30): analog, 7 1/2 ips; full track, mono; 7 in.
    The content starts about 00:00:05. Two male voices; the first sings in a yodeling style. It is unclear which is Ciceron. Other male voices sing in the background. Later in the recording, mixed voices sing in the background. A man sings in a hiccuping style. The recording includes drums, rattles, and other percussion can be heard. There is some hand clapping. Dubbed from one or more source recordings.
    Box panel:
    8 (note de 7) erreur
    Rerecording (3) Canzo Ciceron (suite)
    15' de prieré battemént de me[?]
    a la fin priere catholique
    priere G[?] [?] mache
    [?] a la fin du wire du Canzo 3.
    Rerecording (4) canzo Ciceron début (priere) 20 minutes
    From the leader tape: fin Tape 8 Rerecording Canzo Ciceron 3 (suite) et no 4 (debut)
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 2019/041: SR012; WIRE 01070; 1 sound wire reel (Webster-Chicago, approx. 00:52:00): analog
    Box panel: 52 / Emmanuel / 3 Parreun Cain Hounfor / 4 Damballah Oueddo / 4 Viré Damballah Oueddo / 5 Wo je rele [further details on the box panel; Legba is one of the names]
    Box lid: Emmanuel Vodon - rois / 52'
    Written on the wire spool: Emmanuel chants 52' Chants Sortu de Bande
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 2019/041: SR013; WIRE 01071; 1 sound wire reel (Webster-Chicago, 00:15:00): analog; While the wire's duration is pre-printed on the spool as 15 minutes in duration, the accompanying documentation suggests the recording is 30 minutes long.
    Box panel: Bande Emmanuel - 30' / mascaron / r'aras / Quinbe [?] jes Cagré [?] / 2
    Written on the wire spool: Bande Emmanuel - 30' / mascaron / r'aras
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 2019/041: SR014; WIRE 01072; 1 sound wire reel (Webster-Chicago, approx. 00:52:00): analog; While the wire's duration is pre-printed on the spool as 30 minutes in duration, the accompanying documentation suggests the recording is 52 minutes long.
    Box panel: Box panel 1: No. I / Manger Ste Terre / 52' / à garder rec[?] priere -- Box panel 2: Odette Rigaud
    Box lid: Manger Ste Terre / 52' / no I / à revoir
    Written on the wire spool: Manger St Terre I / 52'
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 2019/041: SR015; WIRE 01073; 1 sound wire reel (Webster-Chicago, approx. 01:00:00): analog
    Box panel 1: passé rerecording I [further details on the box panel] / tape rerecording no 1 et 2
    Box panel 2: rerecording
    Box lid: 3 / Tape 1-2 / Rerecording I / Rada
    Written on the wire spool: passé re recording I
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 2019/041: SR016; WIRE 01074; 1 sound wire reel (Webster-Chicago, approx. 00:15:00): analog
    Box panel: Tape recording no 4 / Rerecording IV I / 5' o madia ové / 3 1/2 Jambé Calfon / 4 Miro Miba / 4 1/2 Panama'm Tombé Congo / Rerecording IV 1 Tape 4
    Box lid: Tape 4 / Rerecording IV - 1
    Written on the wire spool: Rerecording IV / I chants et tambours Petro?
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 2019/041: SR017; WIRE 01075; 1 sound wire reel (unknown duration): analog
    Box panel: rerecording IV 2 / 4 Nago drawd / 4 1/2 Guede Crabigne [?] / 4 1/2 Wago / 3 1/2 Congo / 4 Aux chases [?] / Rerecording sur tape no 4
    Box lid: Tape 4 / Rerecording IV - 2 / 8
    Written on the wire spool: rerecording IV 2 tambourines
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 2019/041: SR018; WIRE 01076; 1 sound wire reel (Webster-Chicago, approx. 01:00:00): analog
    Box panel: Canzo III / a [?] [?] prier[?] jusque 55' / jusque 28' Rerecording sur tape no 8 et 28 ags [?] / tape rerecording no 8
    Box lid: 3 / Tape 7 8 / Canzo III
    Written on the wire spool: 3 / Canzo III rerecording sur tape 7-8
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 2019/041: SR019; WIRE 01077; 1 sound wire reel (Webster-Chicago, approx. 00:30:00): analog
    Box panel: 4' / 2 chants de travailleurs
    Box lid: 10 / 2
    Written on the wire spool: 4' / 2 chants travailleurs
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 2019/041: SR020; WIRE 01078; 1 sound wire reel (Webster-Chicago; approx. 00:30:00): analog
    Box panel: 1 / 5 / Chants de Travailleurs each 10' / Prie non jo [?] / [further details on the box panel]
    Box lid: 1 / 10 / 9 / 5 / chants de travailleurs
    Written on the wire spool: Chants des travailleurs / each 10'
  - Sound recording, November 2, 1949, AFC 2019/041: SR021; WIRE 01079; 1 sound wire reel (Webster-Chicago, approx. 01:00:00): analog
    Box panel: Guedés (Lorgina) / sur assez long apres mon Antoine
    Box lid: 5 / Guédés - 2 Novembre 1949
    Written on the wire spool: Guédés - Lorgina / 2 Novèmbre
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 2019/041: SR022; WIRE 01080; 1 sound wire reel (Webster-Chicago, approx. 00:30:00): analog
    Box panel: Box panel 1: 1/ Odette Ligilia Andoclés 4' / histoire Man Bellande 11' / Milo A[?] 1950 5' / [?]issa etc 8' -- Box panel 2: Lizila Andoclés / Man Bellande / 15'
    Box lid: 1 / Lizila Andoclés / Man Bellande / Milo / 28'
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 2019/041: SR023; WIRE 01081; 1 sound wire reel (Webster-Chicago, approx. 00:15:00): analog; "Bobine" is a reel; probably a reference to the wire spool.
    Box panel: a garder / Bobine II / Debut manger Hounter / 31' + 10' de 4 (B) / Manger Hountor / Bobine II / 31 10' 3 / Odette Rigaud
    Written on the wire spool: III 31' Hounter (A) a garder / + 10' des grande 4 - (B)
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 2019/041: SR024; WIRE 01082; 1 sound wire reel (Webster-Chicago; approx. 00:15:00): analog
    Box panel: Bobine III / 31' / a garder / 4 / Fin Manger Hountor (C)
    Written on the wire spool: Manger Hountor (C) / 31' / 4
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 2019/041: SR025; WIRE 01083; 1 sound wire reel: analog
    Box panel: Antoinette 10' / [?] Congo [?] / Antoinette
    Written on the wire spool: Antoinette / 1 [?]
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 2019/041: SR026; WIRE 01084; 1 sound wire reel (Webster-Chicago): analog
    Box panel: passé vierge
    Written on the wire spool: Milo 25'
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 2019/041: SR027; WIRE 01085; 1 sound wire reel (Webster-Chicago; approx. 00:30:00): analog
    Box panel: [??] B[?] Guede / Banda / Malu / Famille Nada / [?] / Jodon [?] (divers) / Odette Rigaud
    Written on the wire spool: Belecon [further details on the spool]
  - Sound recording, 1950, AFC 2019/041: SR028; WIRE 01086; 1 sound wire reel (Webster-Chicago; approx. 00:30:00): analog
    Box panel: Lorgina [??] / Guedes Lorgina 1950
    Written on the wire spool: Guedes Lorgina 1950
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 2019/041: SR029; RXK 3582; 1 sound tape reel (acetate, 00:48:05): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in.
    The content begins about 00:00:08. Singing with mixed voices. On different songs, a man (possibly more than one man) leads singing, with a sung response from mixed voices. Later in the recording conversations can be heard. The recording includes drums, a rattle, a sound like a cowbell, an unidentified wind instrument. Songs start and end abruptly. The tape was probably was dubbed from one or more wire recordings.
    Information from the donor (written on the tape box): Tape 2 to cassette 2 April 1982 by Shirley Keller
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 2019/041: SR030; WIRE 01087; 1 sound wire reel (Webster-Chicago, approx. 01:00:00): analog
    Box panel: Rerecording III [?] 40' / [??] / Rerecording III Tape 3
    Written on the wire spool: Rerecording III
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 2019/041: SR031; RXK 3583; 1 sound tape reel (acetate, 00:48:00): analog, 7 1/2 ips; half track, mono; 7 in.
    The content begins about 00:00:06. At times a man sings the lead (almost certainly more than one man sings lead, at different times), with a group of mixed voices. Vocal whoops, possibly by a woman, can be heard. The recording includes drums, rattles, and other percussion (both wood and metal). The tape was probably was dubbed from one or more wire recordings.
    Box panel: 3A / [more details in pencil here] / Voodoo [sic] - Rigaud
    Written on the tape reel flange: Head (debut) Rerecording ([?]) 4 - [?]
    Information from the donor (written on the tape box): Tape 3A to cassette April 1982 by Shirley Keller
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 2019/041: SR032; RXK 3584; 1 sound tape reel (acetate, 00:47:33): analog, 7 1/2 ips; half track, mono; 7 in.
    The content begins at 00:00:25. Primarily mixed voices, with occasional lead vocals by a woman and by a man. The recording includes drums and other percussion. The sound fades in and out on occasion. Hand-clapping can be heard towards the end of the recording. The recording ends abruptly. The tape was probably was dubbed from one or more wire recordings.
    Box panel: Rerecording (M) 1 / [more details here]
    Written on the tape reel flange: Side A: 5 1/2 signalé Agoné / 2 1/2 cinna ou cinna / 6' Fai guon [?] neve s[?] yanquilé [?] neve [?] can / 5 african [?] [?] legba Beni da o alyzan aluzan [?] marché / 4 1/2 voco atissan / 3 Coco Coco / 6 Demballah Aveddo [?] / 4 creol' o vodoines [?] Side B: 7 Rèle l.ment [?]. 1 manhaver [?] / 3 salve legba é / 3 Keke salve legba
    Information from the donor (written on the tape box): 3 / Tape 3 to cassette April 1982 by Shirley Keller / Wire Rerecordings from Madame Odette Rigaud - P-au-P. [Port au Prince] Haiti year? 1950s / Bob Avedon made these / Voodoo [sic] tapes from wire Recordings
  - Sound recording, November 12, 1980, AFC 2019/041: SR033; RXK 4059; 1 sound tape reel (backcoated polyester and polyester, 00:19:05): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 5 3/4 in.; The tape is an edited combination of regular and backcoated stocks. The backcoated sections have sticky shed syndrome. The tape was baked before transfer.
    The content begins at 00:00:04. Michael Richards interviews Shirley Keller on Radio Metropol (Haiti). Subjects include the Appalachian dulcimer, the autoharp, Keller's family, educational, and professional backgrounds, her feelings about Haiti (as this was her second visit), her interest in preserving Haitian culture, the book she recently worked on with Diane Wolkstein ( The Magic Orange Tree, and Other Haitian Folktales ), the meaning of the book title, the publication history of the book, how the stories were gathered from various homes, the impact of television and radio on storytelling, an explanation of folk music and the meaning of songs, the difference between country music and folk music, the history of her working relationship with Paul Cadwell and Charlie Wright (a recording of "Music Is A Treat" is played at this point), kazoos, Keller's meeting with Tiroro (also Ti Roro; Raymond Baillargau, dancer/drummer); a recording of his drumming is played (but edited out of this recording), Keller's radio program ("The Folk People"), locations where she has played in Haiti and the response she received, her hope to collect more music in Haiti to present to the American people, and her invitation to Michael Richards to appear on her show.
    Box panel: Imperial / 12 Nov 1980 / Shirley Keller interview / Haiti / 894 595 / Refrains de demain 80/11 / 28' 00" 7 1/2 i.p.s. Francais 28.5.1980 / Philo Anjlach [?] [?] / Tiroro died 1 year ago 1979
    Written on the tape reel flange: Shirley Keller interview 2/27/81
    Information from the donor (written on the tape box): Interviewer - Michael Richards 11-12-80 / Tiroro died 1 year ago 1979
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 2019/041: SR034; RXK 4060; 1 sound tape reel (acetate, 00:48:00): analog, 7 1/2 ips; half track, mono; 7 in.
    The content begins at 00:00:07. A man sings a cappella, and soon after with drum accompaniment. One song has a chorus of children singing. One song seems to be entirely one man singing a capella, and is cut off abruptly. Singing also includes mixed adult voices. Conversations can be heard but the voices are almost unintelligible (as a result of low audio quality). There is occasional sound distortion, either from the source recording's condition, or possibly because the mic was too close to the instruments as they were being played. The recording ends abruptly. Instruments played include drums, metal percussion, and whistles.
    Box panel: [??] Congo [further details on the box panel] / Haiti - Rigaud - Voodoo [sic] / Head - (debut Rerecording (M) Lil Etudes [?] - IV
    Written on the tape reel flange: Tape 4 to cassette 4
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 2019/041: SR035; RYE 8034; 1 sound cassette (Side A: 00:32:30, Side B: 00:29:10): analog, 1 7/8 ips, half track, mono
    Side A: The content begins at 00:00:09. A man sings to drum accompaniment. In another song, men sing lead vocals, to mixed chorus accompaniment. Instruments played include drums, a stringed instrument (possibly a guitar)